<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Information Book</string>

    <string name="united_kingdom">

    <b>Capital:</b>\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t London \n
        <b>Largest City:</b>\t\t\t\t\t\t London \n
        <b>National Language: </b>\t English \n
        <b>Total Area:</b>\t\t\t\t\t\t 242,495 km2 \n
        <b>Currency:</b>\t\t\t\t\t\t GBP \n\n

        \t\t The United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland, commonly known as the United Kingdom (UK) or Britain,[k][14] is a country in Northwestern Europe, off the north-western coast of the continental mainland.[15] It comprises England, Scotland, Wales, and Northern Ireland.[l][16] It includes the island of Great Britain, the north-eastern part of the island of Ireland, and most of the smaller islands within the British Isles.[17] Northern Ireland shares a land border with the Republic of Ireland; otherwise, the United Kingdom is surrounded by the Atlantic Ocean, the North Sea, the English Channel, the Celtic Sea and the Irish Sea. The total area of the United Kingdom is 93,628 square miles (242,495 km2), with an estimated 2023 population of over 68 million people.

\n\n\t\t The United Kingdom has evolved from a series of annexations, unions and separations of constituent countries over several hundred years. The Treaty of Union between the Kingdom of England (which also included Wales) and the Kingdom of Scotland in 1707 resulted in their unification to become the Kingdom of Great Britain. Its union in 1801 with the Kingdom of Ireland created the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Ireland. Most of Ireland seceded from the UK in 1922, leaving the present United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland, which formally adopted its name in 1927.[m] The nearby Isle of Man, Guernsey and Jersey are not part of the UK, being Crown Dependencies, but the British government is responsible for their defence and international representation.[18] The UK became the first industrialised country and was the world\'s foremost power for the majority of the 19th and early 20th centuries, particularly during the Pax Britannic between 1815 and 1914.[19][20] The British Empire, at its height in the 1920s, encompassed almost a quarter of the world\'s landmass and population, and was the largest empire in history; however, its involvement in World War I and World War II, the cumulative crisis and the loss of prestige led to the decolonization of most of the British colonies and the eventual end of the Empire.[21][22][23] A part of the core Anglophonic world, British influence can be observed in the language, culture, legal and political systems of many of its former colonies.

\n\n\t\t The United Kingdom is a constitutional monarchy and parliamentary democracy.[n][25] The capital and largest city of the United Kingdom (as well as the capital of England) is London, a megacity which (alongside New York City) is one of the world\'s two main financial centres. The cities of Edinburgh, Cardiff, and Belfast are respectively the national capitals of Scotland, Wales, and Northern Ireland. Other major cities include Birmingham, Manchester, Glasgow, and Leeds.[26] The UK consists of three distinct legal jurisdictions: England and Wales, Scotland, and Northern Ireland. This is due to these areas retaining their existing legal systems even after joining the UK.[27] Since 1998, Scotland, Wales, and Northern Ireland also have their own devolved governments and legislatures, each with varying powers.[28]
    </string>

    <string name="france">
        <b>Capital:</b>\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t Paris \n
        <b>Largest City:</b>\t\t\t\t\t\t Paris \n
        <b>National Language: </b>\t French \n
        <b>Total Area:</b>\t\t\t\t\t\t 643,801 km2 \n
        <b>Currency:</b>\t\t\t\t\t\t Euro \n\n

    \t\t    France, officially the French Republic,[14] is a country located primarily in Western Europe. It also includes overseas regions and territories in the Americas and the Atlantic, Pacific and Indian Oceans,[XII] giving it one of the largest discontiguous exclusive economic zones in the world. Its metropolitan area extends from the Rhine to the Atlantic Ocean and from the Mediterranean Sea to the English Channel and the North Sea; overseas territories include French Guiana in South America, Saint Pierre and Miquelon in the North Atlantic, the French West Indies, and many islands in Oceania and the Indian Ocean. Its eighteen integral regions (five of which are overseas) span a combined area of 643,801 km2 (248,573 sq mi) and have a total population of over 68 million as of January 2023.[5][8] France is a unitary semi-presidential republic with its capital in Paris, the country\'s largest city and main cultural and commercial centre; other major urban areas include Marseille, Lyon, Toulouse, Lille, Bordeaux, Strasbourg and Nice.

\n\n\t\tInhabited by archaic humans since the Paleolithic era, the territory of Metropolitan France was settled during the Iron Age by Celtic tribes known as Gauls. Rome annexed the area in 51 BC, leading to a distinct Gallo-Roman culture that laid the foundation of the French language. The Germanic Franks formed the Kingdom of Francia, which became the heartland of the Carolingian Empire. The Treaty of Verdun of 843 partitioned the empire, with West Francia becoming the Kingdom of France in 987. In the High Middle Ages, France was a powerful but highly decentralized feudal kingdom. From the mid-14th to the mid-15th centuries, France was plunged into a series of dynastic conflicts involving England, collectively known as the Hundred Years\' War. The French Renaissance saw art and culture flourish and the establishment of a French colonial empire, one of the largest in history.[15] The second half of the 16th century was dominated by the conflict with the House of Habsburg and the religious civil wars between Catholics and Huguenots that severely weakened the country. France was successful in the Thirty Years\' War and further increased its influence during the reign of Louis XIV.[16]
    </string>

    <string name="india">

        <b>Capital:</b>\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t New delhi \n
        <b>Largest City:</b>\t\t\t\t\t\t Mumbai \n
        <b>National Language: </b>\t Hindi \n
        <b>Total Area:</b>\t\t\t\t\t\t 3,287,263[2] km2 \n
        <b>Currency:</b>\t\t\t\t\t\t INR \n\n

        \t\tIndia, officially the Republic of India (ISO: Bhārat Gaṇarājya),[22] is a country in South Asia. It is the seventh-largest country by area; the most populous country as of June 2023;[23][24] and from the time of its independence in 1947, the world\'s most populous democracy.[25][26][27] Bounded by the Indian Ocean on the south, the Arabian Sea on the southwest, and the Bay of Bengal on the southeast, it shares land borders with Pakistan to the west;[j] China, Nepal, and Bhutan to the north; and Bangladesh and Myanmar to the east. In the Indian Ocean, India is in the vicinity of Sri Lanka and the Maldives; its Andaman and Nicobar Islands share a maritime border with Thailand, Myanmar, and Indonesia.

\n\n\t\t Modern humans arrived on the Indian subcontinent from Africa no later than 55,000 years ago.[28][29][30] Their long occupation, initially in varying forms of isolation as hunter-gatherers, has made the region highly diverse, second only to Africa in human genetic diversity.[31] Settled life emerged on the subcontinent in the western margins of the Indus river basin 9,000 years ago, evolving gradually into the Indus Valley Civilisation of the third millennium BCE.[32] By 1200 BCE, an archaic form of Sanskrit, an Indo-European language, had diffused into India from the northwest.[33][34] Its evidence today is found in the hymns of the Rigveda. Preserved by an oral tradition that was resolutely vigilant, the Rigveda records the dawning of Hinduism in India.[35] The Dravidian languages of India were supplanted in the northern and western regions.[36] By 400 BCE, stratification and exclusion by caste had emerged within Hinduism,[37] and Buddhism and Jainism had arisen, proclaiming social orders unlinked to heredity.[38] Early political consolidations gave rise to the loose-knit Maurya and Gupta Empires based in the Ganges Basin.[39] Their collective era was suffused with wide-ranging creativity,[40] but also marked by the declining status of women,[41] and the incorporation of untouchability into an organised system of belief.[k][42] In South India, the Middle kingdoms exported Dravidian-languages scripts and religious cultures to the kingdoms of Southeast Asia.[43]

\n\n\t\t In the early medieval era, Christianity, Islam, Judaism, and Zoroastrianism became established on India\'s southern and western coasts.[44] Muslim armies from Central Asia intermittently overran India\'s northern plains,[45] eventually founding the Delhi Sultanate, and drawing northern India into the cosmopolitan networks of medieval Islam.[46] In the 15th century, the Vijayanagara Empire created a long-lasting composite Hindu culture in south India.[47] In the Punjab, Sikhism emerged, rejecting institutionalised religion.[48] The Mughal Empire, in 1526, ushered in two centuries of relative peace,[49] leaving a legacy of luminous architecture.[l][50] Gradually expanding rule of the British East India Company followed, turning India into a colonial economy, but also consolidating its sovereignty.[51] British Crown rule began in 1858. The rights promised to Indians were granted slowly,[52][53] but technological changes were introduced, and modern ideas of education and the public life took root.[54] A pioneering and influential nationalist movement emerged, which was noted for nonviolent resistance and became the major factor in ending British rule.[55][56] In 1947 the British Indian Empire was partitioned into two independent dominions,[57][58][59][60] a Hindu-majority Dominion of India and a Muslim-majority Dominion of Pakistan, amid large-scale loss of life and an unprecedented migration.[61]

    </string>

    <string name="switzerland">

        <b>Capital:</b>\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t Bern \n
        <b>Largest City:</b>\t\t\t\t\t\t Zurich \n
        <b>National Language: </b>\t Swiss \n
        <b>Total Area:</b>\t\t\t\t\t\t 41,285 km2 \n
        <b>Currency:</b>\t\t\t\t\t\t Swiss franc \n\n

      \t\t  Switzerland, federated country of central Europe. Switzerland’s administrative capital is Bern, while Lausanne serves as its judicial centre. Switzerland’s small size—its total area is about half that of Scotland—and its modest population give little indication of its international significance.

Switzerland
Switzerland
A landlocked country of towering mountains, deep Alpine lakes, grassy valleys dotted with neat farms and small villages, and thriving cities that blend the old and the new, Switzerland is the nexus of the diverse physical and cultural geography of western Europe, renowned for both its natural beauty and its way of life. Aspects of both have become bywords for the country, whose very name conjures images of the glacier-carved Alps beloved of writers, artists, photographers, and outdoor sports enthusiasts from around the world.

\n\n\t\t Grindelwald, Switzerland
\n\n\t\t Grindelwald, Switzerland
\n\n\t\t La Gruyère district, Switzerland
\n\n\t\t La Gruyère district, Switzerland
\n\n\t\t For many outsiders, Switzerland also evokes a prosperous if rather staid and unexciting society, an image that is now dated. Switzerland remains wealthy and orderly, but its mountain-walled valleys are far more likely to echo the music of a local rock band than a yodel or an alphorn. Most Swiss live in towns and cities, not in the idyllic rural landscapes that captivated the world through Johanna Spyri’s Heidi (1880–81), the country’s best-known literary work. Switzerland’s cities have emerged as international centres of industry and commerce connected to the larger world, a very different tenor from Switzerland’s isolated, more inward-looking past. As a consequence of its remarkably long-lived stability and carefully guarded neutrality, Switzerland—Geneva, in particular—has been selected as headquarters for a wide array of governmental and nongovernmental organizations, including many associated with the United Nations (UN)—an organization the Swiss resisted joining until the early 21st century.

    </string>

    <string name="italy">

        <b>Capital:</b>\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t\t Rome \n
        <b>Largest City:</b>\t\t\t\t\t\t Rome \n
        <b>National Language: </b>\t Italian \n
        <b>Total Area:</b>\t\t\t\t\t\t 301,230 km2 \n
        <b>Currency:</b>\t\t\t\t\t\t Euro \n\n

     \t\t   Italy, country of south-central Europe, occupying a peninsula that juts deep into the Mediterranean Sea. Italy comprises some of the most varied and scenic landscapes on Earth and is often described as a country shaped like a boot. At its broad top stand the Alps, which are among the world’s most rugged mountains. Italy’s highest points are along Monte Rosa, which peaks in Switzerland, and along Mont Blanc, which peaks in France. The western Alps overlook a landscape of Alpine lakes and glacier-carved valleys that stretch down to the Po River and the Piedmont. Tuscany, to the south of the cisalpine region, is perhaps the country’s best-known region. From the central Alps, running down the length of the country, radiates the tall Apennine Range, which widens near Rome to cover nearly the entire width of the Italian peninsula. South of Rome the Apennines narrow and are flanked by two wide coastal plains, one facing the Tyrrhenian Sea and the other the Adriatic Sea. Much of the lower Apennine chain is near-wilderness, hosting a wide range of species rarely seen elsewhere in western Europe, such as wild boars, wolves, asps, and bears. The southern Apennines are also tectonically unstable, with several active volcanoes, including Vesuvius, which from time to time belches ash and steam into the air above Naples and its island-strewn bay. At the bottom of the country, in the Mediterranean Sea, lie the islands of Sicily and Sardinia.

\n\n\t\t Italy
\n\n\t\t Italy
\n\n\t\t Italy’s political geography has been conditioned by this rugged landscape. With few direct roads between them, and with passage from one point to another traditionally difficult, Italy’s towns and cities have a history of self-sufficiency, independence, and mutual mistrust. Visitors today remark on how unlike one town is from the next, on the marked differences in cuisine and dialect, and on the many subtle divergences that make Italy seem less a single nation than a collection of culturally related points in an uncommonly pleasing setting.

\n\n\t\t Across a span of more than 3,000 years, Italian history has been marked by episodes of temporary unification and long separation, of intercommunal strife and failed empires. At peace for more than half a century now, Italy’s inhabitants enjoy a high standard of living and a highly developed culture.

\n\n\t\t Though its archaeological record stretches back tens of thousands of years, Italian history begins with the Etruscans, an ancient civilization that rose between the Arno and Tiber rivers. The Etruscans were supplanted in the 3rd century BCE by the Romans, who soon became the chief power in the Mediterranean world and whose empire stretched from India to Scotland by the 2nd century CE. That empire was rarely secure, not only because of the unwillingness of conquered peoples to stay conquered but also because of power struggles between competing Roman political factions, military leaders, families, ethnic groups, and religions. The Roman Empire fell in the 5th century CE after a succession of barbarian invasions through which Huns, Lombards, Ostrogoths, and Franks—mostly previous subjects of Rome—seized portions of Italy. Rule devolved to the level of the city-state, although the Normans succeeded in establishing a modest empire in southern Italy and Sicily in the 11th century. Many of those city-states flourished during the Renaissance era, a time marked by significant intellectual, artistic, and technological advances but also by savage warfare between states loyal to the pope and those loyal to the Holy Roman Empire.

    </string>

    <string name="subhas">

        <b>Born:</b>\t\t\t\t\t\t January 23, 1897 \n
        <b>Died:</b>\t\t\t\t\t\t August 18, 1945 \n
        <b>Nationality:</b>\t Indian \n

       \n\n\t\t Subhas Chandra Bose, byname Netaji (Hindi: “Respected Leader”), (born c. January 23, 1897, Cuttack, Orissa [now Odisha], India—died August 18, 1945, Taipei, Taiwan?), Indian revolutionary prominent in the independence movement against British rule of India. He also led an Indian national force from abroad against the Western powers during World War II. He was a contemporary of Mohandas K. Gandhi, at times an ally and at other times an adversary. Bose was known in particular for his militant approach to independence and for his push for socialist policies.
        \n\n\t\t The son of a wealthy and prominent Bengali lawyer, Bose studied at Presidency College, Calcutta (Kolkata), from which he was expelled in 1916 for nationalist activities, and the Scottish Churches College (graduating in 1919). He then was sent by his parents to the University of Cambridge in England to prepare for the Indian Civil Service. In 1920 he passed the civil service examination, but in April 1921, after hearing of the nationalist turmoils in India, he resigned his candidacy and hurried back to India. Throughout his career, especially in its early stages, he was supported financially and emotionally by an elder brother, Sarat Chandra Bose (1889–1950), a wealthy Calcutta lawyer and Indian National Congress (also known as the Congress Party) politician.
        \n\n\t\t Bose joined the noncooperation movement started by Mohandas K. Gandhi, who had made the Indian National Congress a powerful nonviolent organization. Bose was advised by Gandhi to work under Chitta Ranjan Das, a politician in Bengal. There Bose became a youth educator, journalist, and commandant of the Bengal Congress volunteers. His activities led to his imprisonment in December 1921. In 1924 he was appointed chief executive officer of the Calcutta Municipal Corporation, with Das as mayor. Bose was soon after deported to Burma (Myanmar) because he was suspected of connections with secret revolutionary movements. Released in 1927, he returned to find Bengal Congress affairs in disarray after the death of Das, and Bose was elected president of the Bengal Congress. Shortly thereafter he and Jawaharlal Nehru became the two general secretaries of the Indian National Congress. Together they represented the more militant, left-wing faction of the party against the more compromising, right-wing Gandhian faction.
    </string>

    <string name="nelson">

        <b>Born:</b>\t\t\t\t\t\t 18 July 1918 \n
        <b>Died:</b>\t\t\t\t\t\t  5 December 2013 \n
        <b>Nationality:</b>\t South African \n

        \t\t Nelson Mandela, in full Nelson Rolihlahla Mandela, byname Madiba, (born July 18, 1918, Mvezo, South Africa—died December 5, 2013, Johannesburg), Black nationalist and the first Black president of South Africa (1994–99). His negotiations in the early 1990s with South African Pres. F.W. de Klerk helped end the country’s apartheid system of racial segregation and ushered in a peaceful transition to majority rule. Mandela and de Klerk were jointly awarded the Nobel Prize for Peace in 1993 for their efforts.
        \n\n\t\t Nelson Mandela was the son of Chief Henry Mandela of the Madiba clan of the Xhosa-speaking Tembu people. After his father’s death, young Nelson was raised by Jongintaba, the regent of the Tembu. Nelson renounced his claim to the chieftainship to become a lawyer. He attended South African Native College (later the University of Fort Hare) and studied law at the University of the Witwatersrand; he later passed the qualification exam to become a lawyer. In 1944 he joined the African National Congress (ANC), a Black-liberation group, and became a leader of its Youth League. That same year he met and married Evelyn Ntoko Mase. Mandela subsequently held other ANC leadership positions, through which he helped revitalize the organization and oppose the apartheid policies of the ruling National Party.

\n\n\t\t In 1952 in Johannesburg, with fellow ANC leader Oliver Tambo, Mandela established South Africa’s first Black law practice, specializing in cases resulting from the post-1948 apartheid legislation. Also that year, Mandela played an important role in launching a campaign of defiance against South Africa’s pass laws, which required nonwhites to carry documents (known as passes, pass books, or reference books) authorizing their presence in areas that the government deemed “restricted” (i.e., generally reserved for the white population). He traveled throughout the country as part of the campaign, trying to build support for nonviolent means of protest against the discriminatory laws. In 1955 he was involved in drafting the Freedom Charter, a document calling for nonracial social democracy in South Africa.

\n\n\t\t Mandela’s antiapartheid activism made him a frequent target of the authorities. Starting in 1952, he was intermittently banned (severely restricted in travel, association, and speech). In December 1956 he was arrested with more than 100 other people on charges of treason that were designed to harass antiapartheid activists. Mandela went on trial that same year and eventually was acquitted in 1961. During the extended court proceedings, he divorced his first wife and married Nomzamo Winifred Madikizela (Winnie Madikizela-Mandela).

    </string>

    <string name="winston">

        <b>Born:</b>\t\t\t\t\t\t 30 November 1874 \n
        <b>Died:</b>\t\t\t\t\t\t   24 January 1965 \n
        <b>Nationality:</b>\t British \n

      \t\t  Winston Churchill, in full Sir Winston Leonard Spencer Churchill, (born November 30, 1874, Blenheim Palace, Oxfordshire, England—died January 24, 1965, London), British statesman, orator, and author who as prime minister (1940–45, 1951–55) rallied the British people during World War II and led his country from the brink of defeat to victory.

\n\n\t\t After a sensational rise to prominence in national politics before World War I, Churchill acquired a reputation for erratic judgment in the war itself and in the decade that followed. Politically suspect in consequence, he was a lonely figure until his response to Adolf Hitler’s challenge brought him to leadership of a national coalition in 1940. With Franklin D. Roosevelt and Joseph Stalin he then shaped Allied strategy in World War II, and after the breakdown of the alliance he alerted the West to the expansionist threat of the Soviet Union. He led the Conservative Party back to office in 1951 and remained prime minister until 1955, when ill health forced his resignation.

\n\n\t\t In Churchill’s veins ran the blood of both of the English-speaking peoples whose unity, in peace and war, it was to be a constant purpose of his to promote. Through his father, Lord Randolph Churchill, the meteoric Tory politician, he was directly descended from John Churchill, 1st duke of Marlborough, the hero of the wars against Louis XIV of France in the early 18th century. His mother, Jennie Jerome, a noted beauty, was the daughter of a New York financier and horse racing enthusiast, Leonard W. Jerome.

\n\n\t\t The young Churchill passed an unhappy and sadly neglected childhood, redeemed only by the affection of Mrs. Everest, his devoted nurse. At Harrow his conspicuously poor academic record seemingly justified his father’s decision to enter him into an army career. It was only at the third attempt that he managed to pass the entrance examination to the Royal Military College, now Academy, Sandhurst, but, once there, he applied himself seriously and passed out (graduated) 20th in a class of 130. In 1895, the year of his father’s tragic death, he entered the 4th Hussars. Initially the only prospect of action was in Cuba, where he spent a couple of months of leave reporting the Cuban war of independence from Spain for the Daily Graphic (London). In 1896 his regiment went to India, where he saw service as both soldier and journalist on the North-West Frontier (1897). Expanded as The Story of the Malakand Field Force (1898), his dispatches attracted such wide attention as to launch him on the career of authorship that he intermittently pursued throughout his life. In 1897–98 he wrote Savrola (1900), a Ruritanian romance, and got himself attached to Lord Kitchener’s Nile expeditionary force in the same dual role of soldier and correspondent. The River War (1899) brilliantly describes the campaign.

    </string>

    <string name="abrahim">

        <b>Born:</b>\t\t\t\t\t\t 12 February 1809 \n
        <b>Died:</b>\t\t\t\t\t\t  April 15, 1865 (aged 56) \n
        <b>Nationality:</b>\t American \n

      \t\t  Abraham Lincoln, byname Honest Abe, the Rail-Splitter, or the Great Emancipator, (born February 12, 1809, near Hodgenville, Kentucky, U.S.—died April 15, 1865, Washington, D.C.), 16th president of the United States (1861–65), who preserved the Union during the American Civil War and brought about the emancipation of enslaved people in the United States.

\t\t Lincoln and his cabinet
\n\n\t\t Lincoln and his cabinet
\n\n\t\t Abraham Lincoln: statue at the Lincoln Memorial
\n\n\t\t Abraham Lincoln: statue at the Lincoln Memorial
\n\n\t\t Among American heroes, Lincoln continues to have a unique appeal for his fellow countrymen and also for people of other lands. This charm derives from his remarkable life story—the rise from humble origins, the dramatic death—and from his distinctively human and humane personality as well as from his historical role as saviour of the Union and emancipator of enslaved people. His relevance endures and grows especially because of his eloquence as a spokesman for democracy. In his view, the Union was worth saving not only for its own sake but because it embodied an ideal, the ideal of self-government. In recent years, the political side to Lincoln’s character, and his racial views in particular, have come under close scrutiny, as scholars continue to find him a rich subject for research. The Lincoln Memorial in Washington, D.C., was dedicated to him on May 30, 1922.

    </string>

    <string name="teresa">

        <b>Born:</b>\t\t\t\t\t\t 26 August 1910 \n
        <b>Died:</b>\t\t\t\t\t\t  5 September 1997 \n
        <b>Nationality:</b>\t Indian \n\n

       \t\t Mother Teresa, in full St. Teresa of Calcutta, also called St. Mother Teresa, original name Agnes Gonxha Bojaxhiu, (baptized August 27, 1910, Skopje, Macedonia, Ottoman Empire [now in Republic of North Macedonia]—died September 5, 1997, Calcutta [now Kolkata], India; canonized September 4, 2016; feast day September 5), founder of the Order of the Missionaries of Charity, a Roman Catholic congregation of women dedicated to the poor, particularly to the destitute of India. She was the recipient of numerous honours, including the 1979 Nobel Prize for Peace.

\n\n\t\t The daughter of an ethnic Albanian grocer, she went to Ireland in 1928 to join the Sisters of Loreto at the Institute of the Blessed Virgin Mary and sailed only six weeks later to India as a teacher. She taught for 17 years at the order’s school in Calcutta (Kolkata).
        \n\n\t\t In 1946 Sister Teresa experienced her “call within a call,” which she considered divine inspiration to devote herself to caring for the sick and poor. She then moved into the slums she had observed while teaching. Municipal authorities, upon her petition, gave her a pilgrim hostel, near the sacred temple of Kali, where she founded her order in 1948. Sympathetic companions soon flocked to her aid. Dispensaries and outdoor schools were organized. Mother Teresa adopted Indian citizenship, and her Indian nuns all donned the sari as their habit. In 1950 her order received canonical sanction from Pope Pius XII, and in 1965 it became a pontifical congregation (subject only to the pope). In 1952 she established Nirmal Hriday (“Place for the Pure of Heart”), a hospice where the terminally ill could die with dignity. Her order also opened numerous centres serving the blind, the aged, and the disabled. Under Mother Teresa’s guidance, the Missionaries of Charity built a leper colony, called Shanti Nagar (“Town of Peace”), near Asansol, India.

    </string>

    <string name="britishmuseums">

        <b>Date:</b>\t\t\t\t\t\t 1753 - present \n\n
        \t\t British Museum, in London, comprehensive national museum with particularly outstanding holdings in archaeology and ethnography. It is located in the Bloomsbury district of the borough of Camden.

\n\n\t\t British Museum Reading Room
\n\n\t\t British Museum Reading Room
\n\n\t\t Explore Bloomsbury\'s British Museum, home to the Elgin Marbles and the Rosetta Stone, in London
\n\n\t\t Explore Bloomsbury\'s British Museum, home to the Elgin Marbles and the Rosetta Stone, in LondonSee all videos for this article
\n\n\t\t Established by act of Parliament in 1753, the museum was originally based on three collections those of Sir Hans Sloane Robert Harley, 1st earl of Oxford and Sir Robert Cotton. The collections (which also included a significant number of manuscripts and other library materials) were housed in Montagu House, Great Russell Street, and were opened to the public in 1759. The museum’s present building, designed in the Greek Revival style by Sir Robert Smirke, was built on the site of Montagu House in the period 1823–52 and has been the subject of several subsequent additions and alterations. Its famous round Reading Room was built in the 1850s beneath its copper dome laboured such scholars as Karl Marx, Virginia Woolf, Peter Kropotkin, and Thomas Carlyle. In 1881 the original natural history collections were transferred to a new building in South Kensington to form the Natural History Museum, and in 1973 the British Museum’s library was joined by an act of Parliament with a number of other holdings to create the British Library. About half the national library’s holdings were kept at the museum until a new library building was opened at St. Pancras in 1997.
    </string>

    <string name="vatican">

        <b>Date:</b>\t\t\t\t\t\t 1506, Vatican City \n\n

        \t\t The museums were originally founded in the 16th century by Pope Julius II to display the Vatican’s collection of classical sculptures. The first pieces were laid out in 1506 in the Cortile Ottagono (Octagonal Courtyard), where many remain to this day. Julius also commissioned two of the top artists of the age to work on the Vatican palace – Raphael to decorate his private apartments and Michelangelo to paint the Sistine Chapel.

\n\n\t\t Over successive centuries, the popes continued to add to the collections and open new museums. Major developments included the establishment of the Museo Pio-Clementino in the late 18th century and the opening of the Etruscan and Egyptian museums by Pope Gregory XVI in the 1830s.

\n\n\t\t More recently, Pope John Paul II oversaw a lengthy restoration of the Sistine Chapel and a museum-wide spruce-up for the year 2000 Jubilee.

\n\n\t\t You’ll need about three hours to cover the museums’ greatest hits on this whistle-stop tour.

\n\n\t\t From the Cortile delle Corazze, head through the Cortile della Pigna to the Museo Chiaramonti. Don\'t stop here, but continue left, up the stairs, to the Museo Pio-Clementino where you’ll find the museums’ finest ancient sculpture. Chief among its many masterpieces are the Laocoön and Apollo Belvedere, both in the Cortile Ottagono (Octagonal Courtyard).

\n\n\t\t Finished there, work your way through a series of rooms to the Sala Croce Greca (Greek Cross Room), from where the Simonetti staircase leads up to the Galleria dei Candelabri (Gallery of the Candelabra). Push on through this to the Galleria degli Arazzi (Tapestry Gallery) and Galleria delle Carte Geografiche (Map Gallery), a stunning 120m-long hall lined with remarkable 16th-century maps.

\n\n\t\t At the end of the gallery, the one-way system funnels you through the Sala Sobieski and on to the Stanze di Raffaello (Raphael Rooms), a series of four rooms frescoed by the Renaissance maestro. The star turn here is La Scuola di Atene (School of Athens; 1509–11) in the Stanza della Segnatura but you’ll also find extraordinary works in the Sala di Costantino, Stanza d\'Eliodoro, and Stanza dell\'Incendio di Borgo.

\n\n\t\t Anywhere else these magnificent chambers would be the star attraction but here they’re the warm-up act for the grand finale – the Sistine Chapel.

    </string>

    <string name="hermitage">

        <b>Date:</b>\t\t\t\t\t\t 1764; 259 years ago \n\n

       \t\t Hermitage, in full the State Hermitage Museum, Russian Gosudarstvenny Ermitazh, art museum in St. Petersburg founded in 1764 by Catherine the Great as a court museum. It adjoined the Winter Palace and served as a private gallery for the art amassed by the empress. Under Nicholas I the Hermitage was reconstructed (1840–52), and it was opened to the public in 1852. Following the October Revolution of 1917, the imperial collections became public property, and the museum was expanded in the 1920s with art requisitioned from private collections. In 1930–34, during the push for rapid industrialization, some of the masterpieces were sold by the Soviet government in order to underwrite purchases of industrial machinery from the West. The museum’s collection of late 19th- to early 20th-century European art was expanded substantially in the immediate post-World War II period. The museum is now housed within five interconnected buildings, including the Winter Palace (1754–62) and the Small, Old, and New Hermitages.

\n\n\t\t (Read Sister Wendy’s Britannica essay on art appreciation.)

\n\n\t\t Take a guided tour to the Hermitage Museum in Saint Petersburg, Russia
\n\n\t\t Take a guided tour to the Hermitage Museum in Saint Petersburg, RussiaSee all videos for this article
\n\n\t\t The Hermitage holdings include nearly three million items dating from the Stone Age to the present. Among them is one of the world’s richest collections of western European painting since the Middle Ages, including many masterpieces by Renaissance Italian and Baroque Dutch, Flemish, and French painters. Russian art is well represented. The Hermitage also has extensive holdings of Asian art; especially noteworthy is its collection of the art of Central Asia.

\n\n\t\t Visit the Hermitage Museum
\n\n\t\t Visit the Hermitage MuseumSee all videos for this article
\n\n\t\t The largest of several satellite museums at home and abroad, the Hermitage Amsterdam, opened in the Netherlands in June 2009. Located on the Amstel River in the centre of Amsterdam, it is part of a larger effort to showcase the museum’s treasures in exhibits around the world.

    </string>

    <string name="louvre">

        <b>Date:</b>\t\t\t\t\t\t 10 August 1793 \n\n

        \t\t In 1546 Francis I, who was a great art collector, had this old castle razed and began to build on its site another royal residence, the Louvre, which was added to by almost every subsequent French monarch. Under Francis I, only a small portion of the present Louvre was completed, under the architect Pierre Lescot. This original section is today the southwestern part of the Cour Carrée. In the 17th century, major additions were made to the building complex by Louis XIII and Louis XIV. Cardinal de Richelieu, the chief minister of Louis XIII, acquired great works of art for the king. Louis XIV and his minister, Cardinal Mazarin, acquired outstanding art collections, including that of Charles I of England. A committee consisting of the architects Claude Perrault and Louis Le Vau and the decorator and painter Charles Le Brun planned that part of the Louvre which is known as the Colonnade.

\n\n\t\tLouvre Museum
\n\n\t\tLouvre Museum
\n\n\t\tThe Louvre ceased to be a royal residence when Louis XIV moved his court to Versailles in 1682. The idea of using the Louvre as a public museum originated in the 18th century. The comte d’Angiviller helped build and plan the Grande Galerie and continued to acquire major works of art. In 1793 the revolutionary government opened to the public the Musée Central des Arts in the Grande Galerie. Under Napoleon the Cour Carrée and a wing on the north along the rue de Rivoli were begun. In the 19th century two major wings, their galleries and pavilions extending west, were completed, and Napoleon III was responsible for the exhibition that opened them. The completed Louvre was a vast complex of buildings forming two main quadrilaterals and enclosing two large courtyards.

    </string>

    <string name="indian">

        <b>Date:</b>\t\t\t\t\t\t 2 February 1814; 209 years ago \n\n

        \t\t Indian Museum, in Calcutta, oldest museum in India and one of the most comprehensive in the Orient; its collections depict the cultural history of India from prehistoric to Muslim times. The present building, opened in 1875, comprises sections devoted to geology, zoology, industry, archaeology, art, and ethnology. The coin room contains the largest collection of Indian coins in the world.

\n\n\t\tThe art section is noted for its textiles, carpets, lacquer-work, glass and pottery. The gallery displays examples of Persian and Indian paintings, and the geological section is the largest in Asia and one of the most important in the world. There is a large collection of statues and bronzes from various Asian civilizations, including life-size models of people and animals of the regions of India.

    </string>

    <string name="tajmahal">

        <b>Location:</b>\t\t\tAgra, Uttar Pradesh, India \n
        <b>Built:</b>\t\t\t1631–1653 \n\n

      \t\t  Taj Mahal, also spelled Tadj Mahall, mausoleum complex in Agra, western Uttar Pradesh state, northern India. The Taj Mahal was built by the Mughal emperor Shah Jahān (reigned 1628–58) to immortalize his wife Mumtaz Mahal (“Chosen One of the Palace”), who died in childbirth in 1631, having been the emperor’s inseparable companion since their marriage in 1612. India’s most famous and widely recognized building, it is situated in the eastern part of the city on the southern (right) bank of the Yamuna (Jumna) River. Agra Fort (Red Fort), also on the right bank of the Yamuna, is about 1 mile (1.6 km) west of the Taj Mahal.

\n\n\t\t In its harmonious proportions and its fluid incorporation of decorative elements, the Taj Mahal is distinguished as the finest example of Mughal architecture, a blend of Indian, Persian, and Islamic styles. Other attractions include twin mosque buildings (placed symmetrically on either side of the mausoleum), lovely gardens, and a museum. One of the most beautiful structural compositions in the world, the Taj Mahal is also one of the world’s most iconic monuments, visited by millions of tourists each year. The complex was designated a UNESCO World Heritage site in 1983.

    </string>

    <string name="colosseum">

        <b>Location:</b>\t\t\tRegio III Isis et Serapis, Rome, Italy \n
        <b>Built:</b>\t\t\tAD 70–80; 1943 years ago \n\n

        \t\t Colosseum, also called Flavian Amphitheatre, giant amphitheatre built in Rome under the Flavian emperors. Construction of the Colosseum was begun sometime between 70 and 72 CE during the reign of Vespasian. It is located just east of the Palatine Hill, on the grounds of what was Nero’s Golden House. The artificial lake that was the centrepiece of that palace complex was drained, and the Colosseum was sited there, a decision that was as much symbolic as it was practical. Vespasian, whose path to the throne had relatively humble beginnings, chose to replace the tyrannical emperor’s private lake with a public amphitheatre that could host tens of thousands of Romans.

\n\n\t\t Colosseum
\n\n\t\t The structure was officially dedicated in 80 CE by Titus in a ceremony that included 100 days of games. Later, in 82 CE, Domitian completed the work by adding the uppermost story. Unlike earlier amphitheatres, which were nearly all dug into convenient hillsides for extra support, the Colosseum is a freestanding structure of stone and concrete, using a complex system of barrel vaults and groin vaults and measuring 620 by 513 feet (189 by 156 metres) overall. Three of the arena’s stories are encircled by arcades framed on the exterior by engaged columns in the Doric, Ionic, and Corinthian orders; the structure’s rising arrangement of columns became the basis of the Renaissance codification known as the assemblage of orders. The main structural framework and facade are travertine, the secondary walls are volcanic tufa, and the inner bowl and the arcade vaults are concrete.

    </string>

    <string name="greatwallofchina">

        <b>Location:</b>\t\t\tChina \n
        <b>Built:</b>\t\t\t7th century BCE  \n\n

      \t\t  Great Wall of China, Chinese (Pinyin) Wanli Changcheng or (Wade-Giles romanization) Wan-li Ch’ang-ch’eng (“10,000-Li Long Wall”), extensive bulwark erected in ancient China, one of the largest building-construction projects ever undertaken. The Great Wall actually consists of numerous walls—many of them parallel to each other—built over some two millennia across northern China and southern Mongolia. The most extensive and best-preserved version of the wall dates from the Ming dynasty (1368–1644) and runs for some 5,500 miles (8,850 km) east to west from Mount Hu near Dandong, southeastern Liaoning province, to Jiayu Pass west of Jiuquan, northwestern Gansu province. This wall often traces the crestlines of hills and mountains as it snakes across the Chinese countryside, and about one-fourth of its length consists solely of natural barriers such as rivers and mountain ridges. Nearly all of the rest (about 70 percent of the total length) is actual constructed wall, with the small remaining stretches constituting ditches or moats. Although lengthy sections of the wall are now in ruins or have disappeared completely, it is still one of the more remarkable structures on Earth. The Great Wall was designated a UNESCO World Heritage site in 1987.

\n\n\t\t Explore China\'s iconic cultural monument the Great Wall of China

\n\n\t\t Shanhaiguan
\n\n\t\t Large parts of the fortification system date from the 7th through the 4th century BCE. In the 3rd century BCE Shihuangdi (Qin Shihuang), the first emperor of a united China (under the Qin dynasty), connected a number of existing defensive walls into a single system. Traditionally, the eastern terminus of the wall was considered to be Shanhai Pass (Shanhaiguan) in eastern Hebei province along the coast of the Bo Hai (Gulf of Chihli), and the wall’s length—without its branches and other secondary sections—was thought to extend for some 4,160 miles (6,700 km). However, government-sponsored investigations that began in the 1990s revealed sections of wall in Liaoning, and aerial and satellite surveillance eventually proved that this wall stretched continuously through much of the province. The greater total length of the Ming wall was announced in 2009.

    </string>

    <string name="machupichu">

        <b>Location:</b>\t\t\Cusco Region, Peru \n
        <b>Built:</b>\t\t\tDiscovered in 1911\n\n

        \t\tMachu Picchu, also spelled Machupijchu, site of ancient Inca ruins located about 50 miles (80 km) northwest of Cuzco, Peru, in the Cordillera de Vilcabamba of the Andes Mountains. It is perched above the Urubamba River valley in a narrow saddle between two sharp peaks—Machu Picchu (“Old Peak”) and Huayna Picchu (“New Peak”)—at an elevation of 7,710 feet (2,350 metres). One of the few major pre-Columbian ruins found nearly intact, Machu Picchu was designated a UNESCO World Heritage site in 1983.

\n\n\t\t Hiram Bingham at Machu Picchu
\n\n\t\t Although the site escaped detection by the Spaniards, it may have been visited by the German adventurer Augusto Berns in 1867. However, Machu Picchu’s existence was not widely known in the West until it was “discovered” in 1911 by the Yale University professor Hiram Bingham, who was led to the site by Melchor Arteaga, a local Quechua-speaking resident. Bingham had been seeking Vilcabamba (Vilcapampa), the “lost city of the Incas,” from which the last Inca rulers led a rebellion against Spanish rule until 1572. He cited evidence from his 1912 excavations at Machu Picchu, which were sponsored by Yale University and the National Geographic Society, in his labeling of the site as Vilcabamba; however, that interpretation is no longer widely accepted. (Nevertheless, many sources still follow Bingham’s precedent and erroneously label Machu Picchu as the “lost city of the Incas.”) Evidence later associated Vilcabamba with another ruin, Espíritu Pampa, which was also discovered by Bingham. In 1964 Espíritu Pampa was extensively excavated under the direction of the American explorer Gene Savoy. The site was much deteriorated and overgrown with forest, but Savoy uncovered remains there of some 300 Inca houses and 50 or more other buildings, as well as extensive terraces, proving that Espíritu Pampa was a much larger settlement.

    </string>

    <string name="pyramid">

        <b>Location:</b>\t\t\Giza,Egypt \n
        <b>Built:</b>\t\t\tc. 2575–c. 2465 BCE\n\n

       \t\t Pyramids of Giza, Arabic Ahrāmāt Al-Jīzah, Giza also spelled Gizeh, three 4th-dynasty (c. 2575–c. 2465 BCE) pyramids erected on a rocky plateau on the west bank of the Nile River near Al-Jīzah (Giza) in northern Egypt. In ancient times they were included among the Seven Wonders of the World. The ancient ruins of the Memphis area, including the Pyramids of Giza, Ṣaqqārah, Dahshūr, Abū Ruwaysh, and Abū Ṣīr, were collectively designated a UNESCO World Heritage site in 1979.

\n\n\t\t The designations of the pyramids—Khufu, Khafre, and Menkaure—correspond to the kings for whom they were built. The northernmost and oldest pyramid of the group was built for Khufu (Greek: Cheops), the second king of the 4th dynasty. Called the Great Pyramid, it is the largest of the three, the length of each side at the base averaging 755.75 feet (230 metres) and its original height being 481.4 feet (147 metres). The middle pyramid was built for Khafre (Greek: Chephren), the fourth of the eight kings of the 4th dynasty; the structure measures 707.75 feet (216 metres) on each side and was originally 471 feet (143 metres) high. The southernmost and last pyramid to be built was that of Menkaure (Greek: Mykerinus), the fifth king of the 4th dynasty; each side measures 356.5 feet (109 metres), and the structure’s completed height was 218 feet (66 metres). All three pyramids were plundered both internally and externally in ancient and medieval times. Thus, the grave goods originally deposited in the burial chambers are missing, and the pyramids no longer reach their original heights because they have been almost entirely stripped of their outer casings of smooth white limestone; the Great Pyramid, for example, is now only 451.4 feet (138 metres) high. That of Khafre retains the outer limestone casing only at its topmost portion. Constructed near each pyramid was a mortuary temple, which was linked via a sloping causeway to a valley temple on the edge of the Nile floodplain. Also nearby were subsidiary pyramids used for the burials of other members of the royal family.

    </string>


</resources>